Imtiaz Sabir

+971 50 904 66 15

iamsabir70@hotmail.com



Career Profile

Self-motivated, dedicated and qualified finance professional who endeavors to function with the team as a leader and as a colleague. The objective is learning and self-development, development of the team and organizational success.

Over 15 years of experience in all aspects of hospitality accounting with good knowledge and understanding of financial operations.

Preopening team member of 4 hotel properties out of which two in GCC.

Key Skill

Budgeting and Forecasting, Management of VAT/GST, Cash Flow Management, Standard Operating Procedures, Internal Controls, Financial Reporting, Reconciliation of Accounts, Cost Control and Management, Payroll Management, Credit Policy, Internal and External Audits.

Work Experience

December 2018 to November 2020

Howard Johnson Hotel

Dubai

Financial Controller

The hotel is franchise from Wyndham and is part of the Gromaxx Hotels Management LLC based in Abu Dhabi. The company is operating a dozen hotels in UAE.

Leading a team of 12 members and managing the financial affairs of the company with assistance to the operational department.

September 2017 to November 2018

Accounting & Bookkeeping Services

Provided online Accounting and Bookkeeping services to international clients as a freelancer through one of the largest online work place.

January to August 2017

Al Shiba Properties

Dubai

Accounts Manager

Al Shiba Properties manages the leasing of owned residential and commercial properties. Headed the department and managed the financial affairs of the company.

June 2015 to December 2016

Accounting & Bookkeeping Services

Providing online Accounting and Bookkeeping services to international clients as a freelancer through one of the largest online work place.

Nov 2013 to May 2015

Swiss-Belhotel Corniche

Abu Dhabi

Financial Controller

A four star property formerly The Royal International Hotel having 189 keys, 3 F&B outlets and meeting & Banquet facilities.

Responsibilities include but not limited to Annual Budget and forecast, Internal Controls, Cost Control and Management, Cash Flow Management, Payroll Management, Credit Policy, Reconciliation of Accounts, Financial Reporting, Internal and External Audits.

Dec 2012 to Oct 2013 Lahore

Accounting & Bookkeeping Services

Provided online Accounting and Bookkeeping services to international clients as a freelancer through one of the largest online work place.

Financial Controller

Preopening team member of the first venture of Hospitality Management Holdings in Iraq.

As part of the preopening team have set up the finance department by recruiting and training the staff, coordinated for the installation of all the software systems and implementation of standard operating procedures. Prepared the preopening and first year operational budgets, assisted the operational department in preparing and understanding their departmental budgets and operational procedures.

October 2011 to March 2012

La Gaufrette Co.

Dubai

Finance Manager

La Gaufrette is operating French concept coffee shops and Lebanese restaurants at the prime locations in Dubai. La Gaufrette is operated by Byblos Hospitality in joint venture with Land Mark Hospitality. A number of hotels, outlets, government and corporate clients are served with a vide variety of high quality products.

Responsibilities include implementation of Standard Operating Procedures, Internal Controls, Recipe costing and pricing, Cost Control and Management, Cash Flow Management, Financial Reporting, Internal and external audits.

December 2010 to May 2011

City Seasons Hotel

Muscat

Financial Controller

Promoted and transferred to pre-opening team of four star hotel having 269 keys, first venture of the Bin Ham group outside UAE. Lead the finance department for the successful opening of the hotel, implementation of the software, recruitment and training of the staff, implementation of SOPs and set up of the operational departments.

October 2008 to November 2010

City Seasons Hotel

Dubai

Accounts Manager

Pre-opening team member and lead the finance department of four star hotel having 180 keys, three F&B outlets, meeting and banqueting facilities.

Responsibilities include but not limited to Annual Budget and forecasting, implementation of Standard Operating Procedures, Internal Controls, Cost Control and Management, Cash Flow Management, Financial Reporting, Credit Policy, Payroll Management, Internal and external audits.

June 2008 to September 2008

Southern Travels (Pvt) Ltd.

Islamabad

Financial Controller

Worked as Financial Controller in the Head Office reporting to the Director of Finance. Southern Travels is the GSA for Saudi Arabian Airlines in Pakistan and has license from IATA for issuance of tickets for various other airlines. The company operates around 24 branches in the major cities.

March 2005 to June 2007

Faisalabad Serena Hotel

Faisalabad

Financial Controller

Due to the dedication and commitment as Credit Manager of Islamabad Serena Hotel was able to exceed the agreed targets and in appreciation was promoted as Financial Controller of Faisalabad Serena Hotel.

Responsible as the custodian of the property and representative of Head office whereby the responsibilities include but not limited to the following:

- Smooth operation of all sections of the department which includes Information Technology, General Accounting, Purchase, Cost Control, Payables, Credit, Income Audit, Payroll, General Cashier and outlet cashiers.
- -Ensure timely preparation of Revenue Budget as per the approved marketing plan.

- -Preparation of Capital Expenditure budget, procurement and monitoring.
- -Annual and monthly financial reporting of results to Head Office as per the reporting standards and target dates defined.
- -Smooth conduct of Internal and Statutory Audits.
- -Filing of monthly and annual Income and Sales Tax returns and liaison for their audit.
- -Coordination and implementation of Internal Control measures and procedures with respect to operational results and control of variances.

Induction, training and evaluation of departmental staff for the career development and annual appraisals.

Sept. 2001 to Feb 2005 Islamabad Serena Hotel Islamabad

Credit Manager

Pre-opening team member of the first five star deluxe hotel having 200 keys, member of the leading hotels of the world, located in the heart of the capital city of Islamabad. Major clients were Embassies, Ministries, Government departments and corporate companies.

Jan 2001to Aug 2001 Regent Plaza Hotel Karachi

Assistant Financial Controller

June 1999 to Oct 1999 Swat Serena Hotel Swat

Financial Controller

Oct 1996 to July 1998 Faisalabad Serena Hotel Faisalabad

Assistant Financial Controller

Institute of Chartered Accountants of Pakistan

Karachi

Articleship

Senior Auditor

Four years of practical training from Ford, Rhodes, Robson, Morrow, Chartered Accountants, Karachi (Affiliated with Ernst & Young International) in February 1996.

During training period worked at various levels, which finally concluded as senior in charge of audits. Extensive accounting and audit experience acquired during training and finalizing audits of reputed national & multinational companies.

Education 1991 Karachi University of Karachi

Bachelor of Commerce

1988 Karachi Board of Intermediate & Secondary Education

FSc. Pre-Engineering

1985 Federal Board Islamabad

Matriculation - Science

Software Knowledge

Have good knowledge and experience of working on the following softwares:

Operational Software Opera, Fidelio, Micros.

Financial Software SUN, SUN Financials (Vision), Materials Control, QuickBooks,

Payroll Software Paytrax, Bayan.

Date of birth : March 27, 1970 Nationality : Pakistan **Current Address** : Aiman, UAE

Visa Status : Visit visa, valid till Dec 10, 2021

References

Can be furnished upon request.